let's look at the solution for our
direct mapped cache access quiz we have
these four accesses in this cache the
cache block is 32 bytes and there are
eight blocks in the cache so the address
break down will be the offset bits will
be 5 because we need 5 bits to tell us
which of the 32 bytes we are talking
about the index bits will be 3 because
we need 3 bits to tell us which of the
eight slots in the cache to use and the
remaining bits are going to be the tag
now let's consider which of these map
we're in the cache
as you can see the least significant 8
bits are going to determine where in the
cache something goes so we can
conveniently look at just the least
significant two hex digits one F is 0 0
0 1 1 1 1 1 5 bits are the offset and 0
0 0 is the index so this goes here 3 F 2
F has 0 0 1 0 here and then 1 1 1 1 1
but it goes to index 1 3 F 2 e has to
and then e it also maps here because it
is actually the same block as this one
they will both be in this slot here
because really the entire block 3 F 2
something is there and finally 3 e 1 F
is going to map to 0 0 1 F so the index
is 0 and it's a different block from the
one we had previously so this one will
be replaced by this so the final content
of the cache really is that the block 3
e 1 something is here and 3 F 2
something is here